<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non-volatile Memory</title>
    <link>https://nvram.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Non-volatile Memory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nvram.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile, Dev(Sec)Ops, SRE, et al. - Finding the common thread for business</title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/posts/agile-devops-sre-common-thread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/posts/agile-devops-sre-common-thread/</guid>
      <description>In the past three decades, the Information Technology industry has seen the rise of many new methodologies, architectures and movements that purport to deliver certain benefits like improved team communication &amp;amp; coordination, directional agility, production quality &amp;amp; consistency, and faster customer feedback, to name a few. While these methodologies have differing foci, I believe that fundamental value provided to a business is the same for all of them. At their core, they enable businesses to use technology to move the demand curve for their product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Managed Services and the Market for Self-Managing Services</title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/posts/managed-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/posts/managed-services/</guid>
      <description>Managed Services in the public cloud are important information technology value accelerators and there is a significant opportunity for third parties to provide businesses with Self-Managing Services in cloud marketplaces that provide a similar value proposition. There&amp;rsquo;s no denying that managed services in the public cloud provide a great value by allowing businesses to avoid a fair bit of muck and, instead, apply their efforts to areas that will make more of a difference to the bottom line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/posts/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/posts/goals/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for 2019 is to grow occupationally through increased confidence. The way I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to tackle this goal is through intentional, periodic publication of my thoughts and ideas on this website. By doing this, I hope to achieve better balance between learning new things (which I love to do), and sharing what I have learned publicly. This should help increase my confidence as I shed my worries about saying the wrong thing, or saying it the the wrong way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/layouts/partials/footer_custom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/layouts/partials/footer_custom/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>