<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non-volatile Memory</title>
    <link>https://nvram.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Non-volatile Memory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nvram.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Managed Services and the Market for Self-Managing Services</title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/posts/managed-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/posts/managed-services/</guid>
      <description>Managed Services in the public cloud are important information technology value accelerators and there is a significant opportunity for third parties to provide businesses with Self-Managing Services in cloud marketplaces that provide a similar value proposition. There&amp;rsquo;s no denying that managed services in the public cloud provide a great value by allowing businesses to avoid a fair bit of muck and, instead, apply their efforts to areas that will make more of a difference to the bottom line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a URL Shortener on AWS using the AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/posts/an-aws-cdk-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/posts/an-aws-cdk-example/</guid>
      <description>With the introduction of the AWS CDK, there&amp;rsquo;s a great new way to create cloud resources on Amazon Web Services. I have been kicking the tires on it since watching the re:Invent talk &amp;ldquo;Infrastructure is Code&amp;rdquo; a few weeks ago. What I have found will not be surprising to anyone who comes from a software engineering background - using an actual* programming language for creating cloud resources is a much more enjoyable experience than writing CloudFormation templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage AWS Saml Roles for G Suite Users</title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/posts/manage-aws-saml-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/posts/manage-aws-saml-roles/</guid>
      <description>I recently setup G Suite (aka Google Apps for Work) as the SAML IdP for my personal AWS account following these instructions. Once it was done, I had a very simple way to log into my AWS console using my existing G Suite credentials.
Now I no longer need to remember my IAM user password (well, it was in a password manager, but it&amp;rsquo;s one less thing) and I get the additional benefit of my G Suite-configured MFA settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>https://nvram.io/posts/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nvram.io/posts/goals/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for 2019 is to grow occupationally through increased confidence. The way I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to tackle this goal is through intentional, periodic publication of my thoughts and ideas on this website. By doing this, I hope to achieve better balance between learning new things (which I love to do do), and sharing what I have learned publicly. This should help increase my confidence as I shed my worries about saying the wrong thing, or saying it the the wrong way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>